# Jared Hennessy

E-MAIL jared.hennessy@gmail.com

### **PROFILE**

Full-stack developer, data analyst, and manager, experienced in solutions architecture and data warehouse modeling for an ever-broadening array of projects.

In my career, I've specialized in database design & efficient ETL architecture and have built reporting solutions & automated business processes across a variety of industries; including marketing, manufacturing, professional services, security, and scientific research. I am ever enthusiastic about the ways in which data assets can both inform and transform operational strategy.

Proficient in database development & building custom data management solutions and dashboards with a variety of tools: complex T-SQL queries, stored procedures, and functions, multidimensional and tabular OLAP cubes in SQL Server Analysis Services, ETL processes in SQL Server Integration Services, and rendering tools such as HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Tableau, Excel + PowerPivot/Power View or VBA, Power BI + SharePoint, and SQL Server Reporting Services.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Immune Tolerance Network – Seattle, Washington

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR, DATA COLLABORATION TEAM, OCTOBER 2018 - PRESENT

### DATA ANALYST/PROGRAMMER, OCTOBER 2016 - OCTOBER 2018

- Design and implement a new data warehouse solution with a next-generation quality management system (QMS) for the ongoing management specimen inventory
- Gather requirements and plan for eventual storage and reporting of clinical trial results data in the next-gen specimen inventory warehouse
- Maintain and develop the automated load of new and changing data sources into the existing specimen inventory warehouse
- · Conduct analysis of existing data warehouse to identify and resolve large amounts of discrepant data
- Rapid analysis and validation of Experimental Plan data to ensure completeness of clinical trial result data
- Gather requirements and develop reports in Power BI as needed, along with any underlying processes necessary to make this data available
- Maintain existing reports and datasets on an ad hoc basis by resolving bugs in existing SSIS packages and SSRS queries

### Matisia Consulting - Seattle, Washington

### SENIOR CONSULTANT, MAY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

- Design a data model to integrate & store performance metrics, identify the causes of poor user experience, and escalate these issues appropriately
- Leverage Azure tools, SQL Server 2016, and SQL Server Integration Services to populate the reporting data model from numerous sources, including both relational and unstructured databases.
- Build out a reporting dashboard with a Tabular cube and accompanying Power BI/Power Pivot reports
- Build an alert system to guide support technicians to the appropriate section of the dashboard for context when a KPI breaches a pre-defined threshold

## Marquis Leadership – Bellevue, Washington SENIOR CONSULTANT, JANUARY 2015 – MAY 2016

• Design and implement Business Intelligence Data Warehouse solutions by integrating disparate data sources with a master data management service to provide a flexible, near-real time data feed to key decision-makers

- Train Tableau users to "self-serve" by connecting directly to their data and building reports, often without the benefit of a data warehouse or dedicated BI developers
- Create development roadmaps by gathering requirements & priorities from stakeholders, cataloguing and analyzing available data sources, and making recommendations about any software purchases that may be necessary

# Piraeus Consulting (formerly Piraeus Data) – Seattle, Washington DIRECTOR OF SOLUTIONS DEVELOPMENT, 2012 – 2014

BI DEVELOPMENT TEAM MANAGER, 2009 – 2012

SENIOR BI DEVELOPER, 2008 - 2009

### Management Responsibilities

- Gather requirements and assist clients in planning high-impact custom development solutions
- Drive sales engineering process: responding to RFPs, making technical & process-based recommendations, scoping the maximum-value work within bid & budget
- Ensure success of project delivery across multiple initiatives by managing resource assignments and monitoring milestone deadlines.
- Hire & mentor a team of developers, keeping them engaged with projects and internal initiatives
- Manage relationships between development team and clients as well as other internal teams, particularly PMO & Business Analytics.
- Maximize efficiency across a team of developers with different skills, experience, and project assignments

### Technical Responsibilities

- Design relational database schemas and OLAP cubes and to facilitate reporting
- Build ETL processes to merge data sources and apply business rules
- Develop dashboards for Microsoft marketing teams to report on audience engagement using multiple data sources and metrics
- Deploy reports using custom web controls, SSRS reports, Excel, etc.

# comScore, Inc. (formerly M:Metrics, Inc.) – Seattle, Washington PRODUCT OPERATIONS MANAGER, 2006 – 2008

- Populate client reporting interfaces for three MS SQL Server & ASP .NET-driven product offerings by combining
  multiple data sources, designing the necessary schema, scripting ETL processes, and working with measurement
  sciences team to maintain data quality
- Manage a team responsible for the collection, classification, and publication of market research data for the mobile sector, specializing in media consumption and advertising
- Set monthly schedule for inputs from other team members while coding custom tools to simplify or automate these contributions
- Provide support for client analytics team by developing schemata for reporting tools, populating these with transformed data, and creating custom reports using custom SQL queries and SSRS

# Various contract positions – Houston, Texas

**DATABASE DEVELOPER, 2005** 

- Develop ETL processes to warehouse data from Excel, Access, Oracle, and MS SQL Server sources
- Develop reporting interfaces for these data sources in Crystal Reports, Access w/ VBA, or ASP
- Optimize guery performance by indexing and normalizing data
- Document underlying database schema and report logic

### **UTC Fire & Security – Houston, Texas**

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR & DEVELOPER, 2000 - 2004

- Maintain data integrity, query performance, and security for two production MS SQL Server 2000 installations for approximately 75 users along with associated test environments
- Assist development of custom C# applications by creating tables, views, and stored procedures as well as developing forms and interfaces in ASP

- Import and normalize data from flat files and propagate throughout system to ensure seamless transition of services
- Create reports using Crystal Reports, Access queries, and scheduled Data Transformation Services packages
- Serve as a functional/technical interface with end users to design software solutions that support business needs and train users as functionality expands

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts, English Literature Rice University, Houston, TX May 2000